American Colonization Society Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- IV: Financial Papers, 1818-1963 (Box IV: 1-96, Reel 251-285)
  - Monrovia, Liberia, journal accounts, 1839, Mar, 20-1847, Dec. 30 (Box IV: 75, Reel 283)
  - Check stubs, 1863-1865, William McLain (Box IV: 76, Reel 283)
  - Memoranda of legacies, 1851-1876 (Box IV: 77, Reel 283)
  - Accounts of rents, 1891-1904 (Box IV: 78)
  - Rents, 1904-1906 (Box IV: 79)
  - Receipt book, 1845, Jan. 4-1861, May (Box IV: 80, Reel 284)
  - Receipts, 1851-1853 (Box IV: 81, Reel 284)
  - Invoice book, 1860-1861 (Box IV: 82, Reel 284)
  - Register of letters, 1832 (Box IV: 83, Reel 284)
  - Bills payable, 1842
  - Accounts payable, 1899 (Box IV: 84)
  - Accounts receivable
    - 1893-1909
    - 1893-1901 (Box IV: 85)
  - Stock book, 1851-1862 (Box IV: 86, Reel 285)
  - Stock inventory, 1841, Jan. 1-1851, Sept. (Box IV: 87, Reel 285)
  - Liberia inventory, 1851 (Box IV: 88, Reel 285)
  - Store inventory, 1828 (Box IV: 89, Reel 285)
  - Daybook, 1828, Mar. 26-Nov. 1
  - Account book, National Bank of Washington (Box IV: 90, Reel 285)
    - 1869, Oct. 2-1890, June 30
    - 1890, July-1892, Mar. 22 (Box IV: 91, Reel 285)
  - Record of accounts, Graham legacy fund, 1871, Dec. 12-1876, Sept. 30 (Box IV: 92, Reel 285)
  - James Saul fund, 1883-1888
  - Register of payments, 1820-1832 (Box IV: 93, Reel 285)
  - List of contributions, 1820-1832 (Box IV: 94, Reel 324*)
    *Containers IV:94-IV:96 were filmed out of sequence
  - Contributions, 1832-1834 (Box IV: 95, Reel 324)
  - Expenditures, 1832-1834
  - Record of contributions, 1832 (Box IV: 96, Reel 324)
  - Medicines sent to Liberia
- V: Business Papers, 1816-1963 (Box V: 1-57, Reel 286-299)
  Annual reports, proceedings and minutes of the annual meetings of the board of directors and the executive committee, membership and donation records, and papers concerning the African Repository.
  - Annual reports and special reports, 1818, 1840, 1843-1855 (Box V:1, Reel 286)
  - Annual reports (Box V:2, Reel 286)
    - 1856-1866
    - 1867-1876 (Box V:3, Reel 287)
    - 1877-1884 (Box V:4, Reel 287)
    - 1885-1888 (Box V:5, Reel 288)
    - 1889-1892 (Box V:6, Reel 288)
  - Proceedings, 1816, Dec. 21-1825, Feb. 19; constitution (Box V:7, Reel 289)
  - Board of managers (Box V:8, Reel 289)
    - Proceedings, 1817, Mar. 4-1828, Oct. 15
    - Minutes (Box V:9, Reel 289)
      - 1828, Oct. 17-1833, Dec. 18
      - 1834, Jan. 6-1842, Jan. 20 (Box V:10, Reel 290)
    - Proceedings, 1842, Jan. 20-1869, Jan. 20 (Box V:11, Reel 290)
    - Minutes (Box V:12, Reel 290)
      - 1869, Jan. 19-1912, Feb. 8
      - 1913-1923 (Box V:13, Reel 291)
      - 1923-1952 (Box V:14, Reel 291)
      - 1953, Jan. 20-1963, Feb. 16 (Box V:15, Reel 291)
  - Docket for executive committee meetings (Box V:16, Reel 291)
    - 1859, June 4-1868, Sept. 18
    - 1868, Oct. 2-1879, Mar. 7 (Box V:17, Reel 291)
    - 1879, Apr. 4-1893, Apr. 6 (Box V:18, Reel 291)
  - Board of directors, executive committee journal (Box V:19, Reel 292)
    - 1838, Dec. 13-1845, Mar. 14
    - 1845, Apr.-1854, Dec. (Box V:20, Reel 292)
    - 1855, Jan. 12-1868, Dec. 4 (Box V:21, Reel 292)
    - 1869, Jan. 15-1886, Nov. 4 (Box V:22, Reel 293)
    - 1886, Dec. 26-1912, Feb. 26 (Box V:23, Reel 293)
  - Annual meeting minutes (Box V:24, Reel 294)
    - 1864-1871
    - 1872-1878 (Box V:25, Reel 295)
    - 1879-1885 (Box V:26, Reel 296)
    - 1885-1891 (Box V:27, Reel 296)
  - Executive committee minutes, 1895, Nov. 12
  - Board of directors minutes, extracts, 1838-1863
  - Bylaws of the board of managers adopted, 1827, Jan. 25
  - Board of directors and executive committee miscellany
  - African Repository subscription book (Box V:28, Reel 297)
    - Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, and Michigan, 1846-1858
    - Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and Connecticut, 1845-1857 (Box V:29, Reel 297)
    - Pennsylvania, Delaware, District of Columbia, Maryland, and foreign, 1845-1856 (Box V:30, Reel 297)
    - Maine, New Hampshire, and Vermont, 1845-1856 (Box V:31, Reel 297)
    - Virginia, North Carolina, and South Carolina, 1845-1855 (Box V:32, Reel 297)
    - 1845-1856, bills sent, 1869 (Box V:33, Reel 297)
    - Accounts, 1840-1848 (Box V:34, Reel 297)
  - Subscription book (Box V:35, Reel 297)
    - Kentucky, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, and Michigan
    - North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, and Alabama (Box V:36, Reel 297)
    - Missouri, Iowa, Wisconsin, Minnesota, and California (Box V:37, Reel 297)
    - Maine, New Hampshire, and Vermont (Box V:38, Reel 297)
    - New York, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania (Box V:39, Reel 298)
  - African Repository subscription lists (Box V:40, Reel 298)
  - Newspaper subscription list (Box V:41, Reel 298)
  - New England subscribers, 1845-1876 (Box V:42, Reel 298)
  - Subscription book, 1846-1854, A-M (Box V:43, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers (Box V:44, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers (Box V:45, Reel 298)
  - Subscription book, 1846-1855 (Box V:46, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers (Box V:47, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers, 1854-1858 (Box V:48, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers (Box V:49, Reel 298)
  - List of subscribers (Box V:50, Reel 299)
    - 1849-1875
    - 1846-1856 (Box V:51, Reel 299)
    - 1846-1855 (Box V:52, Reel 299)
    - African Repository, vol. 13, index (Box V:53, Reel 299)
    - Subscription lists (Box V:54, Reel 299)
    - Membership list, circa 1881-1891 (Box V:55, Reel 299)
    - Original subscription list, 1817 (Box V:56, Reel 299)
    - List of life members (Box V:57, Reel 299)
- VI: Subject File, 1792-1964 (Box VI: 1-23, Reel 300-315)
  Correspondence, manuscripts, reports, legal papers, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Acquisition of land in Africa, 1821 (Box VI:1, Reel 300)
  - Acquisition of St. Paul's territory, journal, treaty, accounts, and miscellany, 1825-1826 (printed copies and an 1831 draft)
  - Advisory committee on education in Liberia and Booker Washington Agricultural and Industrial Institute, Kakata, Liberia, *Advisory committee file was filmed out of order (Box VI:1, Reel 302*)
    - 1929-1934
    - 1935-1939 (Box VI:2, Reel 301)
    - 1940 (Box VI:3, Reel 302)
  - African Repository miscellany
  - Agents of the society
  - Agreements concerning recaptured Africans
  - Agreements regarding U.S. Government stores in Liberia, 1844
  - American Colonization Society v. Kelly, 1931-1932
  - Analostan Island and Georgetown property, Washington, D.C.,1901-1936
  - Auxiliary societies
  - Bacon, Samuel, extracts from journal
  - Benjamin Coates Primary School, 1892-1893
  - Benjamin Coates fund
  - Bills of lading, 1845-1865
  - Booker Washington Agricultural and Industrial Institute, Kakata, Liberia
    - 1928-1933
    - 1933-1940, minutes of trustee meetings
    - 1939-1952 (Box VI:4, Reel 303)
  - Port de Bordeaux, commerce avec le Sénégal, 1892
  - Right Reverend Robert E. Campbell, 1926-1933
  - Charter parties, 1843-1865
  - Colonization building, 450 Pennsylvania Ave., Washington, D.C., 1911-1930, May
  - Congressional bills regarding trade and commerce, 1890-1894
  - Constitution of the American Colonization Society, draft (Box VI:5, Reel 304)
  - Contracts with U.S. government
  - Crozer, Samuel A., biographical material
  - Currency
  - Dailey v. American Colonization Society
  - Deeds
    - Charles Irving to John Coles, 1792
    - Lands in Africa, 1822-1834
    - Purchase agreements, 1840-1845
    - 1846-1848
    - 1859-1872
  - Documents regarding dispute between Governor Thomas Buchanan and Methodist missionaries, 1840-1841
  - Donovan, Caroline
    - Trust fund
      - 1910-1919
      - 1920-1924 (Box VI:6, Reel 305)
    - Court papers
  - Education in Liberia and Booker Washington Agricultural and Industrial Institute, Kakata, Liberia
    - 1942-1945
    - 1950 (Box VI:7, Reel 306)
  - Emigration
    - List of applicants for passage to Liberia, 1850-1893
    - 1912-1921, undated
    - 1914-1934 (Box VI:8, Reel 307)
  - Gibson, Nugent H., former agent in Liberia, 1910-1928
  - Golconda (ship)
    - General
    - Partial loss, 1868-1871
  - Graham trust fund, 1910-1925
  - Graham School No. 1, reports, 1896-1911
  - Graham School No. 2, reports, 1897-1904
  - Graham School No. 3, reports, 1898-1911
  - Graham School No. 4, reports, 1899-1900
  - Hall School, 1891-1909 (Box VI:9, Reel 308)
  - History
  - Hurd, Samuel, estate, 1843-1872
  - Indentures
  - Industrial Home School, report, 1902
  - Inventory of office furnishings, circa 1910
  - Johnson, Henry L. E., 1912-1915
  - Johnson, William G., 1919-1929
  - Jones, James David, biographical material
  - “The Junk Establishment” (Box VI:10, Reel 309)
  - Kosciuszko, Thaddeus, wills and estate, 1798-1827
  - Land holdings in Liberia, 1915
  - Lane Seminary Trustees v. American Colonization Society, 1929-1932
  - League of Nations, 1933
  - Legal papers, miscellaneous
  - Liberia College, Monrovia, Liberia, 1918-1936
  - Liberia
    - Government of
    - Agreement between Republic of Liberia and American Colonization Society, 1848
    - “Sketch of the History of Liberia”
    - Neutrality of Liberia, 1914
    - Resolutions for closer relations with England
    - Treaty with native kings, 1840, Apr. 6
    - Visit of Henry L. West in 1932
  - Liberian loan, 1920-1921
  - Life membership certificates
    - Plate
    - Samples
  - Lusk, Robert, estate, 1853-1857 (Box VI:11, Reel 310)
  - Lyon, Ernest, consul general of Liberia in the United States, 1913-1921
  - McLain, William, nomination and appointment as minister of Liberia to the United States, 1850
  - Manuscripts
  - Manuscripts, articles, and reports, circa 1940-1948
  - Manuscript articles on Africa by Hugh Thomas Douglas, 1889, (3 folders)
  - Manuscript regarding early colonization efforts of the American Colonization Society
  - Manuscript “England and Liberia”
  - Manuscript “Steam Communication between the United States and the West Coast of Africa,” by E. E. Smith
  - Manuscript regarding Liberia by Henry L. West
  - Maps
  - Map of Liberia, 1845
  - Maps of Liberia, 1857, 1862
  - Map of Liberia by Hugh Thomas Douglas, 1889
  - Maryland in Liberia, resolutions on the death of James Hall and John H. B. Latrobe (Box VI:12, Reel 311)
  - Membership
  - Milton, Thomas Hector, 1937
  - Miscellaneous lists of names, unidentified
  - Miscellany
  - New York State Colonization Society
  - Overs, Reverend Walter H., 1922-1926
  - Oxley, Howard W., 1931
  - Pennsylvania Colonization Society, resolutions on the death of Elliot Cresson, 1854
  - Peters, John R., legacy, 1914-1919
  - Petitions to Congress
  - Plans and specifications for cottages in Liberia
  - “Plan of the town of Messurado, Western Africa,” 1823, Apr.
  - “Platt of lands Located in the Settlement of Johnsonville.... .”
  - Sibley, James L., 1925-1929
  - Sippel, Franz, 1924-1927
  - Smith, E. E., agent of the society, report of Oct. 1892
  - Smith, Oliver, estate, 1859-1861
  - State Department, 1922-1925, 1932-1936
  - Stevens, John, Maryland State Colonization Society v. American Colonization Society, 1868
  - Stevens v. American Colonization Society, 1923-1924 (Box VI:13, Reel 312)
  - Treaties
  - Trust funds
    - Histories of
    - Miscellaneous
  - Virginia, an act making appropriations for the removal of free persons of color, 1850
  - Walker, Walter F., agent in Liberia, 1914-1921
  - “A West African Journey,” by Claude A. and Etta Moten Barnett, 1947 (Box VI:14, Reel 313)
  - West, Henry L., 1929-1939
  - Wills
    - A-P
    - Myers, Margaret J.
    - R-Z (Box VI:15, Reel 314)
  - Wills and estates, printed matter regarding H. F. Worley, 1920-1922
  - Register of emigrants, 1835, Mar. 4-1857, July 3 (Box VI:16, Reel 314)
  - Emigration register, 1820-1832 (Box VI:17, Reel 314)
  - Applicants for emigration, 1826-1856 (Box VI:18, Reel 314)
  - Applicants for passage to Liberia, 1856-1889 (Box VI:19, Reel 314)
  - Laws and land records of Liberia (Box VI:20, Reel 315)
  - Travel pictures of Liberia by J. Buttikofer, 1890
  - “The One Thousand Agents,” circa 1856
  - “An Essay on the Late Institution of ’The American Society for Colonizing Free People of Colour of the United States'”
- VII: Miscellany, 1835-1935 (Box VII: 1-10, Reel 316-323)
  Unidentified indexes and memorandum books, printed matter, and newspaper clippings.
  - Unidentified indexes (Box VII:1, Reel 316)
  - Miscellaneous memorandum books
  - Map, survey for Booker Washington Institute, Kakata, Liberia, 1935
  - Printed matter (Box VII:2-3, Reel 317-318)
  - Printed matter (Box VII:4, Reel 319)
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Printed matter, including issues of African Repository, 1835-1892, and Liberia Bulletin, 1905-1909 (Box VII:5, Reel 320-321)
  - Clippings
  - Newspaper clippings (Box VII:6, Reel 322)
    - 1892-1893
    - 1893-1894
    - 1894-1895 (Box VII:7, Reel 323)
    - 1895-1896
    - 1896-1898
    - 1898-1899 (Box VII:8, Reel 323)
    - 1899-1901
    - 1901-1903
    - 1903-1905 (Box VII:9, Reel 323)
    - 1905-1909
    - 1909-1910
    - 1913-1916 (Box VII:10, Reel 323)